ARIFUR RAHMAN

2301 - 10 Teesdale Place, Toronto, ON, M1L1K9 | PH (647) 299 2743 | arifrahman@hotmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With 11 years of Financial Experience at BMO Bank of Montreal, I am looking to combine my solutions-driven, collaborative and creative approach to problem solving with my recent Full Stack Web Development certificate to make a positive impact in an technology forward institution

SKILLS

- Working knowledge in Javascript
- Working knowledge in HTML/ CSS
- Successful in independent and team environments
- Analytical and detail oriented
- Multilingual in Bengali and Hindi

- Working knowledge in MySQL
- Problem solving proven to make intelligent and creative decisions quickly
- Experienced operating Microsoft Office and Visual Basic

WORK HISTORY

Loan Support Officer – Specialized Sales Support Center : Sep 2015 - Present **BMO Bank of Montreal – Toronto, ON**

- o Part of a specialized team providing lending solutions to high net worth clients that come to the bank as referrals
- o Complete complex loan funding to adhere with audit requirements
- Maintain and expand relationships with lending specialists, referral sources and customers that cannot be serviced by typical bank channels by providing efficient resolution focused customer service
- Proactively created over 20 different processes simplifying official company policies and legal requirements to improve team efficiency.
- Implemented several new types of document preparation methods, increasing personal productivity by 500% and increasing success rate of signing (said documents) from 50% to 95%
- ✓ Informally led a team of 6 for the last 2 years for a specialized lending package that oversees the disbursement of about \$9 million in new loans to about 500 customers, all within a 4 week period
- ✓ Officially recognized as top performer once a quarter for the last 3 years.

Customer contact agent – Centralized Mortgage Renewals: Nov 2010 – Sep 2015 BMO Bank of Montreal – Mississauga, ON

- · Arrange financing solutions by taking and processing lending applications from clients
- · Attend to clients with maturing home financing and investment products via outbound and inbound calls
- Consistently explore financial needs with client to ensure client's financial success and increasing the banks wallet share.
- Ensure every client who leaves is happy by taking ownership of their concerns, empathizing and outlining the steps that will be taken to fulfill their request and finally resolving the matter in the most efficient manner possible.
- Programmed an excel chart now used by the team to estimate hypothetical penalties for breaking closed mortgage terms.
- Proven to immediately implement changes at work to improve productivity and adapt to a consistently evolving work environment.
- · Helped with training of new hires into the teams by having them shadow my role and reverse shadow

Direct Banking Manager – Proactive sales: Sep 2006 – Nov 2010 BMO Bank of Montreal – Toronto, ON

- · Managed banking for clients by streamlining their account for efficiency
- Identified and pursued new business opportunities through customer conversations
- Empathized with client escalations while providing them first contact resolutions
- Provided the Proactive team with tools that has improved call quality

CERTIFICATION

BMO PLE - Personal Lending -2013

EDUCATION

University of Toronto / Trillium - Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp -- 2019

McMaster University - Hamilton, ON - 2008

- Completed 3rd year Economics
- Completed 2nd year Chemical Engineering